



MANISH RAJENDRA MISAR

Mobile: (+91)-9967867035 | Email: manish0357@gmail.com

Career Summary: 11 years

Oracle Experience: 11 years Postgres Experience: 7 years

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Database Design.
- Data backup and retrieval.
- Oracle.
- PostgreSQL.
- PGAdmin.
- Patroni (Postgres Replication)
- Point in time recovery(PITR Postgres)
- Excellent communication skills.
- Excellent diagnostic skills.
- UNIX shell scripting.
- Oracle RAC, Data guard, RMAN and ASM.
- Postgresql replication.
- Performance Tuning ,Optimization and pg tune.
- Worked on PowerBi report.
- PG DUMP and PG BASEBACKUP
- Database Vacuuming.
- Pgpool ,pgbouncer and pgtune.

Database	Oracle 9i/10g/11g/12c/19c. PostgreSQL 9.5,9.6,10,12.2, 12.3 and 12.13
Database Tools	RMAN, OEM, SQL developer, pgadmin , pg_dump, pg_dumpall, pg_basebackup, Patroni, pgtune
Operating Systems	Linux, AIX, Sun solaris, Windows

Role:

Currently working as Database Project Manager and handling team of 40+ DBA's and also working as Postgresql L3-L4 level DBA actions. Strongly focused and knowledgeable Database Administrator with a wide breadth of database maintenance, installation, Upgradation and migration knowledge. Expert communicator of complex technological concepts of professional and non-professional audiences. Leader of independent workshops in database technologies and implementation in broader professional community.

Certification:

- ORACLE Certified Associate 11g
- Oracle 12c R2: RAC Administration
- ITIL 4







• YEP (Young Emerging Professional)

Experience Summary:

Having 10+ Years of experience as Senior Oracle and 6+ experience as L3 level PostgreSQL Database Administrator involved in backup and recovery methodologies, monitoring database performance. etc. Having support & troubleshooting experience in 24x7 environments.

Experience in Remote PostgreSQL and Oracle Server setup, Database design and Architect.

Expertise In:

- Installation of Postgresql 9,10,11 and 12 version.
- Postgresql minor patching from 10.2 to 10.20 version and 12.3 to 12.13 version.
- Administering large PostgreSQL databases.
- Designing and managing PostgreSQL database schemas experience in security access control also having experience with configuration management and access control.
- Hands on position responsible for configuring, integrating and maintaining PostgreSQL databases.
- Responsible for all backup, recovery and upgrading PostgreSQL databases.
- Patroni and ETCD implementation for replication process for Postgres database.
- Patorni and ETCD troubleshooting for any error and checking sync status.
- Performance tuning the database server at Instance, SQL, Memory, Disk I/O and at OS level.
- Planned and implemented DR & high availability solutions using streaming replication.
- Delivering PostgreSQL Database performance-tuning/troubleshooting services for customers using pg_stat_statements, pg_store plans, pgbadger etc.
- Performance tuning of queries by checking various performance parameters, vacuuming, partitioning, deadtuples, blocking queries etc.
- Backup strategies using pg_dump, pg_dumpall and pg_basebackup.
- Also used pgpool and pgbouncer to increase performance.
- Pg_badger used to analyze performance issue if any by taking logfiles.
- DB creation, user authentication, cloning, DB refresh activity (restoration form one DB to another).
- We have updated 10.2 postgres version to 12.2 version using pg_upgrade tool.
- We used pg_tune tool to check config parameter values as it aligned with its total memory available.
- Participated in all phases of the system development life cycle from requirements analysis through system implementation.
- Auditing, Trouble shooting, Monitored and tuned database performance.
- Collaborated with development team to tackle database/application issues.
- Involved in all phases of database development, from needs assessment to QA/QC, design, and support.
- Exposure to oracle utility RMAN for backups and AWR/ADDM reports from Oracle 10g/11g database and analyzed the reports for identifying on-going/proactive issues, Oracle wait events, time consuming SQL queries, table spaces growth, and database growth.
- Expertise in Analysis, Design, Development, & Implementation of Business Applications using Oracle 10g/11g (SQL, Performance Tuning).
- Tuning autovacuum parameters to ensure up to date table stats and reclaim space consumed by dead tuples
- Prepares and/or reviews activity, progress, and performance reports.
- Diagnoses, resolves and implements preventive measures to prevent problems for availability, recoverability and performance of all supported database environments.





- Install, configure, test, monitor and upgrade new and existing PostgreSQL databases.
- Proactive managing standby replication methodologies like Streaming replication and hot standby for disaster recovery.
- Scheduling daily Point in time recovery (PITR) to the development environment for proper product testing.
- Developed and tested storage strategies and disaster-recovery plan for large manufacturing company's operational database, delivering solution that guaranteed recovery performance and high availability.
- Enhanced users' understanding of database systems by conducting pre-implementation workshops, delivering group and individual training sessions and creating user-friendly training materials.
- Installation of Oracle 9i/10g/11g/12c on Linux/Windows/AIX platform.
- Cross platform Migration from AIX to Sun Solaris for Oracle version 11g database to Oracle 12c using export and import.
- Upgradation of Oracle 11g database to Oracle 12c.
- Migration of MYSQL database to Oracle 12c using SQL developer utility.
- Applying Oracle Security and PSU patches.
- Installation of oracle 12c client on Linux/AIX platform.
- Good exposure to Manual Backup and Recovery techniques using RMAN.
- Cloning of database using RMAN.
- Basic network troubleshooting.
- Pro-active monitoring of Database on Daily and weekly basis.
- Writing OS scripts for backup and executing scripts, Scheduling cron jobs.
- Documentation Report/Review Site Documents, System Study, Backup Policy, Security
 Policy, Performance Management Document, Patch Management Document, Activity Report, Incident Report,
 Monthly Service Report etc.
- RAC Database installation and monitoring and RMAN backup restoration.

Projects Summary: Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. (Feb 2017 – Till Date)

Client: PEPS SILCA CREDIT AGRICOLE.

Role: Database Project Manager (PostgreSQL database Administrator)

Responsibilities:

- Managing 3000+ database overall in that handling 600+ postgres database.
- Good knowledge in PostgreSQL database architecture and Primary components.
- Installation and Configuration of Postgres instance.
- Experience in PostgreSQL cascading/multiple replication on PostgreSQL 10.
- Manage backup and recovery functions for a PostgreSQL using PG DUMP and PG BASEBACKUP.
- Collaborate with development, architecture, and release teams, providing architectural design recommendations, driving standards for effective PostgreSQL transition to production operations.
- Upgrade from PostgreSQL database version 9.5 to 9.6,10 and changing environment server to server.
- Experience in PostgreSQL Installation 9.5, 9.6, 10 Production support.
- Expert in Backup & Recovery including PG dump, setting up WAL archiving, Point in time recovery.
- Monitoring the production PostgreSQL alert logs for database errors.
- Check Alert Log errors and make necessary actions to rectify them.
- Limiting the memory space and granting the necessary roles.



ACCREDITED TRAINING ORGANIZATION PeopleCert on Behalf of AXELOS

- Monitor the client connectivity using pg hba.conf files.
- Patroni and ETCD implementation for replication process for Postgres database.
- Patorni and ETCD troubleshooting for any error and checking sync status.
- Performance Tuning the database server at Instance, SQL, Memory, Disk I/O and at OS level.
- Planned and implemented DR & high availability solutions using streaming replication.
- Delivering PostgreSQL Database performance-tuning/troubleshooting services for customers using pg_stat_statements, pg_store plans, pgbadger etc.
- Cross platform Migration from AIX to Sun Solaris for Oracle version 11g database to Oracle 12c using export and import.
- Upgradation of Oracle 11g database to Oracle 12c.
- Migration of MYSQL database to Oracle 12c using SQL developer utility.
- Applying Oracle Security and PSU patches.
- Installation of oracle 12c client 32 and 64 bit on Linux/AIX platform.
- Switchover and Switchback of DR database using DGBROKER utility.
- Purging of historical data after taking table level export.
- Handling client Request and change using service online request utility.
- Resolving client incident in stipulated time.
- Actively participate in Oracle automation technique using Jenkins tool.
- Actively participate in Oracle DDBoost backup migration utility.
- Resolved Oracle ACL issue on 11.2.0.3 database.
- Actively co-ordinate and handled data center switchover PSI activity.
- Completed training and Certification course for ITIL-4.
- Completed Classroom Training for RAC 12.2.0.2 database new features in Oracle.
- Performance tuning using AWR report to minimize CPU load.

Projects Summary: Company Clover Infotech Pvt ltd (Jan 2013 – Jan 2017)

Client: SBI life Insurance. (Dec 2014 – Jan 2017) Role: Consultant Oracle Database Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Handling 40 Production Databases, 38 Standby DR, 10 report and 60 Test Databases of size 5 GB to 4 TB.
- Supporting and Managing all the Production, Physical Standby & Development databases.
- Creating and altering the primary database storage structures (table spaces)
- Managing Backup and recovery (Online Backup & Offline Backups).
- User Management-creating users, granting, revoking roles, Space management.
- Creating database for Testing/Development.
- Verifying all instances are up and Running, all alert log files for any new entries.
- Creation of oracle Users, Roles, Granting Privileges and Profiles.
- Creating the Clone/Refresh of database.
- Rebuilding indexes to remove fragmentation.
- Creating Physical Standby database.
- Taking Import and Export depending up on requirement.





- Backup contingency to check all backups are proper.
- Cascading of Failover and DR database with production.
- Closure of SCD (Secure Configuration Document) oracle security points like creating locking mechanism, enabling audit, Listener password etc.
- Refreshing actuarial database on monthly basis using Business Copy tool.
- Monthly offline RMAN backups of all production databases.
- Periodic restoration of database from old tape to check backup consistent.
- OEM database monitoring, Cloud database, creating incidents and add target database and hosts.
- RAC Database monitoring and RMAN backup restoration.
- Golden gate configuration in oracle database cross platform (HP-UX to LINUX RHEL).
- Documentation Report/Review Site Documents, System Study, Backup Policy, Security Policy, Performance Management Document, Patch Management Document, Activity Report, Incident Report, Monthly Service Report etc.

Client: PIDILITE INDUSTRIES LIMITED (Jan 2013 – Dec 2014)
Role: Technical Associate Oracle Database Administrator

Responsibilities:

Educational Qualification: B.E (Information Technology Engineering) Mumbai University.

Academic Credentials:

- 1. 2012 B.E in Information Technology from Yadavrao Tasgaokar College of Engg. & Management, Mumbai University 67.53%.
- 2. 2009 Diploma in Information Technology from Shreeram Polytechnic Airoli, Mumbai University secured 74.27%.
- 3. 2006 H.S.C. in science R.K.T. College Ulhasnagar, Mumbai Board secured 53.33%.
- 4. 2004 S.S.C. N.R.C. Colony school Mohone, Mumbai Board secured 76.26%.

Personal Details:

1. Date of Birth: 18th Aug 1988

2. Address: A1 – 304, Shankeshwar Palace, Rambaug 4 end, Kalyan (W).

3. Languages known: English, Hindi, Marathi.

4. Hobbies and interests: Watching Movies (SCI-FI) based, Google Reviewer.

Contact details: 9967867035
PAN CARD details: BADPM7395C

I confirm that, the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.





Certified Associate	PeopleCert ON BEHALF OF AXELOS
ate:	Manish Misar